<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Einar Broch Johnsen&#39;s Homepage</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Einar Broch Johnsen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 10:33:05 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hub341504972d314b2e9a402ad2e73d67e_181309_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remaro: Reliable AI for Marine Robotics</title>
      <link>/project/remaro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 10:33:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/remaro/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Journey Mining: Towards successful digitalisation of services</title>
      <link>/project/sjm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 10:32:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/sjm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The digitalisation of our society&amp;rsquo;s service systems has fundamentally changed the way services are delivered to, and experienced by, humans. Although digital services are supposed to simplify our lives and increase our efficiency, they often frustrate and burden customers, users, and employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall goal is to increase the quality of services and support the successful digitalisation of services by uniting research on process mining and customer journeys using new developments in logic-based analysis and artificial intelligence. The partners are SINTEF Digital, University of Oslo, and Eindhoven University of Technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on user journeys we will analyse, model, and observe how humans experience digital services, rather than taking the perspective of service providers and service systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main source of data comes from two complementary service providers: GrepS, a start-up company offering software services for analysing programming skills, and Telenor, a telecom company offering a wide range of mobile-, broadband- and TV services in the Nordics and in Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will trace data left from users in various systems during repeated interactions with a service over time, on the level of individuals.
In the first phase of the project, we will build tools for automated capture of repeated user interactions in digital channels. Based on the resulting database of user journeys and user models, we will use logic-based techniques and machine learning to expose deviations and predict possible behaviours. The accumulation of user journeys will also enable identification of patterns that optimize the user experience and service quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will extend and use executable modelling languages and their associated analysis tools to describe, predict, and prescribe user journeys as concurrent processes. We will base these languages and analysis tools on formal methods and concurrency theory, which build on the foundation of theoretical computer science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cumulus: Semantics-Based Analyses for Cloud-Aware Computing</title>
      <link>/project/cumulus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 22:17:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/cumulus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cumulus is a project funded by the Research Council of Norway 2015-2019. The main goal of Cumulus is to develop a semantic foundation for static analysis techniques for cloud-aware applications. Cloud-awareness enables the software to negotiate its own quality of service and opens for dynamic and fine-grained resource management. This introduces an element of reflection which goes beyond the state of the art in both formal semantics and static analysis. The project will develop a formal foundation for cloud-aware computing and use this foundation to enable the verification of quantitative assertions about the high-level quality of service and low-level resource requirements of cloud-aware applications. The project will develop demonstrators for the approach in terms of semantics-based tools to analyze quantitative assertions for quality of service during the design of such applications. Cumulus will enable a shift in the design of virtualized software from model simulation and monitoring deployed systems to advanced static analyses of worst-case resource requirements early in the software design&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyVar : Scalable Hybrid Variability</title>
      <link>/project/hyvar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 22:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/hyvar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HyVar was an EU H2020 research project 2015-2018. The idea was to develop a framework for continuous software evolution in distributed systems which combines the description of evolution as a software product line, a scalable cloud infrastructure to monitoring and customization of software upgrades for remote devices, and over-the-air upgrade technologies&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UpScale: From Inherent Concurrency to Massive Parallelism through Type-based Optimizations</title>
      <link>/project/upscale/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 22:16:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/upscale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UpScale was an EU FP7 FET Open-X research project 2014-2017. The idea
was to design programming languages for the manycore era, when a
program can make use of potentially millions of processors. UpScale
used incremental type-based program annotations specifying
deployment-related information, and for innovative type-based
deployment optimisations both at compile- and runtime. The Encore
language was designed in this project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Envisage: Engineering Virtualized Services</title>
      <link>/project/envisage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 22:15:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/envisage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I  coordinated this EU FP7 research project 2013-2016. The basic idea was to integrate service-level agreements (SLA) into the interfaces of an object-oriented model and validate SLA for cloud computing at design time using formal methods. The Envisage project delivered novel methods for predicting the behavior of software deployed on the cloud, using formal models and analysis techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HATS: Highly Adaptable and Trustworthy Software using Formal Methods</title>
      <link>/project/hats/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 21:55:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/hats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HATS was a four-year FET project funded under the EU&amp;rsquo;s FP7 programme 2010-2013.
In the project, we propose to take an empirically successful, yet informal software development paradigm and put it on a formal basis. Specifically, in HATS we will turn software product family (SWPF) development into a rigorous approach. The technical core of the project is an Abstract Behavioral Specification language which will allow precise description of SWPF features and components and their instances. The main project outcome is a methodological and tool framework achieving not merely far-reaching automation in maintaining dynamically evolving software, but an unprecedented level of trust while informal processes are replaced with rigorous analyses based on formal semantics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
