<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Einar Broch Johnsen</title>
    <link>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ebjohnsen.org/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 10:33:05 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ebjohnsen.org/media/icon_hub341504972d314b2e9a402ad2e73d67e_181309_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Digital Twin for Vaccination Strategies at Geographic Scales</title>
      <link>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/pandemics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 10:33:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/pandemics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Digital Twin for Vaccination Strategies at Geographic Scales&lt;/em&gt; project is
the first  internal research project of UiO&amp;rsquo;s Centre for Pandemics and One-Health Research (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.med.uio.no/sustainit/english/centres/p1h/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;P1H&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main objective:&lt;/strong&gt; To develop a digital twin model that enables predictions of transmission given varying levels of efficacies against current and future viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to demonstrate the potential of digital twins to understand
the effects of different vaccine strategies for &amp;ldquo;Pandemic X&amp;rdquo;, the next
pandemic with an unknown pathogen. We will explore the effects of
different strategies through “what-if” experiments using digital twin
technology. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_twin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;digital
twin&lt;/a&gt; is a modelling
framework that integrates real-time sensor data with model-based
predictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, we will devise digital twin models to study likely
future pandemic scenarios, combining in silico models with real-world
data to make experiments as realistic as possible. The digital twin
technology will enable us to explore many different scenarios, by
means of “what if” experiments with a highly configurable model. Our
starting point is a digital twin framework which models a pandemic
emergence at the global scale (see our previous work [&lt;a href=&#34;https://ebjohnsen.org/publication/23-pnas&#34;&gt;PNAS 2023&lt;/a&gt;]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this project, we have composed an interdisciplinary team including
leading experts on vaccine development, epidemiology, digital twins
and philosophy of science, from the Departments of Immunology,
Biosciences, Informatics and Philosophy at UiO. The team further
includes renowned international experts in epidemiology and economy
for consideration of various strategies of vaccine distribution
locally and globally. A focus is on training early-stage researchers
towards preparedness for the next pandemics and endemics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Principal Investigators&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ebjohnsen.org/&#34;&gt;Einar Broch Johnsen&lt;/a&gt; (Department of Informatics, project leader)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.med.uio.no/klinmed/english/people/aca/gunnveig/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gunnveig Grødeland&lt;/a&gt; (Department of Immunology, Faculty of Medicine)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hf.uio.no/ifikk/english/people/aca/philosophy/temporary/anderstr/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Anders Strand&lt;/a&gt; (CPS/IFIKK, Faculty of
Humanities)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mn.uio.no/english/people/adm/fac/research/nilsst/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nils Chr. Stenseth&lt;/a&gt; (P1H &amp;amp; IBV/MN)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project further involves &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.med.uio.no/sustainit/english/people/adm/jasonwh/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jason
D. Whittington&lt;/a&gt;
(P1H) and a very strong international network, including collaborators
from Penn State University (US), King&amp;rsquo;s College London (UK),
University of Oxford (UK), Tsinghua University (CN).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Digital Twin of the Oslo Fjord</title>
      <link>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/oslofjord/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 10:33:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/oslofjord/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Digital Twin of the Oslo Fjord is a project funded by the
&lt;em&gt;Sustainable development&lt;/em&gt; initiative of the Faculty of Mathematics and Natural
Sciences at UiO 2022-2025 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mn.uio.no/english/about/news-and-events/news/kd-positions-sustainable-development-initiative-20.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;more info here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our main goal is to demonstrate the potential of digital twins to
understand the effects of climatic stressors on marine systems, as an
instrument to monitor these climatic stressors in near real time, and
to explore thresholds in the ecosystem for the effect of climatic
stressors through “what-if” experiments using digital twin
technology. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_twin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;digital
twin&lt;/a&gt; is a modeling
framework that integrates real-time sensor data with model-based
predictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We collaborate with &lt;a href=&#34;https://friskoslofjord.no&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Frisk Oslofjord&lt;/a&gt;, a
project that collects data from the fjord. Frisk Oslofjord provides
real-time and historical data about salinity, temperature, oxygen,
plankton, etc. in the Oslo Fjord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This digital twin will be used in the context of ongoing digital twin
activities at UiO and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://uio.no/dscience&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;dScience&lt;/a&gt;
center. The digital twin will ultimately enable semantic analysis and,
building on that, data visualization by oceanographers and other
interested members of the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;system-architecture&#34;&gt;System Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The digital twin architecture is currently being developed using
&lt;a href=&#34;https://smolang.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SMOL&lt;/a&gt;, a language developed at UiO specifically
for digital twins. SMOL integrates simulators of physical systems with
semantic web technologies and time-series databases. The system
architecture will be released as ooeb source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-if-scenarios-for-ecosystem-stressors&#34;&gt;What-If Scenarios for Ecosystem Stressors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our aim to use the Digital Twin of the Oslo Fjord as a laboratory to
explore hypothetical &amp;ldquo;what-if&amp;rdquo; experiments, describing scenarios that
capture human and climatic stressors on the ecosystems of the
fjord. The twin combines physical and biological models of the fjord
and its ecosystems. Experts in computer scientists, marine biology,
oceanography and physics to capture both the physical and biological
effects of such stressors. As an example of ongoing research, we study
the effect of extreme weather events on the circulation model of the
fjord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Digital Twin of the Oslo Fjord is also part of the project
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mn.uio.no/ibv/english/research/sections/aqua/research-projects/coastal-ecosystems&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Coastal Ecosystems Dynamics Under Anthropogenic
Pressures&lt;/a&gt;,
which aims to improve marine sustainability and our understanding of
the dynamics in the coastal zone where land and open sea meet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Master students involved in the Oslo Fjord Digital Twin project:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;André Finstad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vebjørn Olsen Leihne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Janaaththan Muthiah Manokaran&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mariann Løtvedt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sander Sigmundstad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ingvild Emilie Øvsthus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Researchers involved in the Oslo Fjord Digital Twin project&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ebjohnsen.org/&#34;&gt;Einar Broch Johnsen&lt;/a&gt; (computer science, Dept. of Informatics, UiO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mn.uio.no/english/people/adm/fac/research/nilsst/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nils Chr Stenseth&lt;/a&gt; (marine ecology, Dept. of Biosciences, UiO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mn.uio.no/ibv/english/people/aca/alexaei/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Alexander Eiler&lt;/a&gt; (marine ecology, Dept. of Biosciences, UiO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mn.uio.no/math/english/people/aca/atlej/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Atle Jensen&lt;/a&gt; (fluid mechanics, Dept. of Mathematics, UiO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mn.uio.no/geo/english/people/aca/metos/kaihc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kai Håkon Christensen&lt;/a&gt; (oceanography, Norwegian Meteorological Institute)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.fr/citations?user=RWVXUdYAAAAJ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jean Raubault&lt;/a&gt; (oceanography, Norwegian Meteorological Institute)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mn.uio.no/cees/english/people/researcher-postdoc/jentoft/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sissel Jentoft&lt;/a&gt; (marine ecology, Dept. of Biosciences, UiO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://edkamb.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eduard Kamburjan&lt;/a&gt; (computer science, Dept. of Informatics, UiO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apferscher.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Andrea Pferscher&lt;/a&gt;  (computer science, Dept. of Informatics, UiO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mn.uio.no/ifi/english/people/aca/rudi/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Rudolf Schlatte&lt;/a&gt;  (computer science, Dept. of Informatics, UiO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://larswd.github.io/content/intro.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lars Willas Dreyer&lt;/a&gt; (fluid mechanics, Dept. of Mathematics, UiO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mn.uio.no/ifi/?vrtx=person-view&amp;amp;uid=riccasi&amp;amp;lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Riccardo Sieve&lt;/a&gt; (computer science, Dept. of Informatics, UiO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uio.no/dscience/english/people/administration/laura-slaughter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Laura Ann Slaughter&lt;/a&gt; (dScience Center, UiO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mn.uio.no/ifi/english/people/aca/sltarifa/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Silvia Lizeth Tapia Tarifa&lt;/a&gt; (computer science, Dept. of Informatics, UiO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NebulOuS: A Meta Operating System for Brokering Hyper-Distributed Applications on Cloud Computing Continuums</title>
      <link>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/nebulous/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 10:33:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/nebulous/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NebulOuS is a Horizon Europe project,
funded by the European Commission 2022-2025 (project no 101070516).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NebulOuS will accomplish substantial research contributions in the
realms of cloud and fog computing brokerage by introducing advanced
methods and tools for enabling secure and optimal application
provisioning and reconfiguration over the cloud computing
continuum. NebulOuS will develop a novel Meta Operating System and
platform for enabling transient fog brokerage ecosystems that
seamlessly exploit edge and fog nodes, in conjunction with multi-cloud
resources, to cope with the requirements posed by low latency
applications. The envisaged solution includes the following main
directions of work:&lt;br&gt;
i. Development of appropriate modelling methods and tools for
describing the cloud computing continuum, application requirements,
and data streams; these methods and tools will be used for assuring
the QoS of the provisioned brokered services. &lt;br&gt;
ii. Efficient comparison of available offerings, using appropriate
multi-criteria decision-making methods that are able to consider all
dimensions of consumer requirements. &lt;br&gt;
iii. Intelligent applications, workflows and data streams management
in the cloud computing continuum. &lt;br&gt;
iv. Addressing in a unified manner the security aspects emerging in of
transient cloud computing continuums (e.g., access control, secure
network overlay etc.). &lt;br&gt;
v. Conducting and monitoring smart contracts-based service level
agreements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remaro: Reliable AI for Marine Robotics</title>
      <link>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/remaro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 10:33:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/remaro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Remaro is a Marie Skłodowska-Curie (MSCA) European Training Network
funded by the European Commission 2020-2024 (project no 956200). CORDIS website &lt;a href=&#34;https://cordis.europa.eu/project/id/956200&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The network will educate 15 PhD research fellows on complimentary
aspects of reliable autonomy for underwater robotic applications. The
REMARO research fellows will develop the first ever submarine robotics
AI methods with quantified reliability, correctness specifications,
models, tests, and analysis &amp;amp; verification methods.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Journey Mining: Towards Successful Digitalisation of Services</title>
      <link>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/sjm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 10:32:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/sjm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SJM is a project funded by the Research Council of Norway
2021-2024. The partners are SINTEF Digital (coordinator), University
of Oslo, and Eindhoven University of Technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall goal of SJM is to increase the quality of
service and support the successful digitalisation of services by
uniting research on process mining and customer journeys using new
developments in logic-based analysis and artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The digitalisation of our society&amp;rsquo;s service systems has fundamentally changed the way services are delivered to, and experienced by, humans. Although digital services are supposed to simplify our lives and increase our efficiency, they often frustrate and burden customers, users, and employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall goal is to increase the quality of services and support the successful digitalisation of services by uniting research on process mining and customer journeys using new developments in logic-based analysis and artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on user journeys we will analyse, model, and observe how humans experience digital services, rather than taking the perspective of service providers and service systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main source of data comes from two complementary service providers: GrepS, a start-up company offering software services for analysing programming skills, and Telenor, a telecom company offering a wide range of mobile-, broadband- and TV services in the Nordics and in Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will trace data left from users in various systems during repeated interactions with a service over time, on the level of individuals.
In the first phase of the project, we will build tools for automated capture of repeated user interactions in digital channels. Based on the resulting database of user journeys and user models, we will use logic-based techniques and machine learning to expose deviations and predict possible behaviours. The accumulation of user journeys will also enable identification of patterns that optimize the user experience and service quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will extend and use executable modelling languages and their associated analysis tools to describe, predict, and prescribe user journeys as concurrent processes. We will base these languages and analysis tools on formal methods and concurrency theory, which build on the foundation of theoretical computer science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cumulus: Semantics-Based Analyses for Cloud-Aware Computing</title>
      <link>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/cumulus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 22:17:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/cumulus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cumulus was a FRINATEK project funded by the Research Council of
Norway 2015-2019. I was the project leader of CUMULUS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main goal of Cumulus is to develop a semantic foundation for static analysis techniques for cloud-aware applications. Cloud-awareness enables the software to negotiate its own quality of service and opens for dynamic and fine-grained resource management. This introduces an element of reflection which goes beyond the state of the art in both formal semantics and static analysis. The project will develop a formal foundation for cloud-aware computing and use this foundation to enable the verification of quantitative assertions about the high-level quality of service and low-level resource requirements of cloud-aware applications. The project will develop demonstrators for the approach in terms of semantics-based tools to analyze quantitative assertions for quality of service during the design of such applications. Cumulus will enable a shift in the design of virtualized software from model simulation and monitoring deployed systems to advanced static analyses of worst-case resource requirements early in the software design&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyVar : Scalable Hybrid Variability for Distributed Evolving Software Systems</title>
      <link>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/hyvar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 22:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/hyvar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HyVar was an EU H2020 research project 2015-2018 (project no
644298). I was the scientific coordinator of HyVar.
CORDIS website &lt;a href=&#34;https://cordis.europa.eu/project/id/644298&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was to develop a framework for continuous software evolution in distributed systems which combines the description of evolution as a software product line, a scalable cloud infrastructure to monitoring and customization of software upgrades for remote devices, and over-the-air upgrade technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UpScale: From Inherent Concurrency to Massive Parallelism through Type-based Optimizations</title>
      <link>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/upscale/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 22:16:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/upscale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UpScale was an EU FP7 FET Open-X research project 2014-2017 (project
no 612985).  CORDIS website &lt;a href=&#34;https://cordis.europa.eu/project/id/612985&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was to design programming languages for the
manycore era, when a program can make use of potentially millions of
processors. UpScale used incremental type-based program annotations
specifying deployment-related information, and for innovative
type-based deployment optimisations both at compile- and runtime. The
Encore programming language was designed in this project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Envisage: Engineering Virtualized Services</title>
      <link>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/envisage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 22:15:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/envisage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Envisage was an  EU FP7 research project 2013-2016 (project no 610582).
I was the coordinator of Envisage.  CORDIS website &lt;a href=&#34;https://cordis.europa.eu/project/id/610582&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic idea was to integrate service-level agreements (SLA) into the interfaces of an object-oriented model and validate SLA for cloud computing at design time using formal methods. The Envisage project delivered novel methods for predicting the behavior of software deployed on the cloud, using formal models and analysis techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project website &lt;a href=&#34;http://envisage-project.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HATS: Highly Adaptable and Trustworthy Software using Formal Methods</title>
      <link>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/hats/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 21:55:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/hats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HATS was a four-year FET project funded under the EU&amp;rsquo;s FP7 programme
2010-2013 (project no 231620).  CORDIS website &lt;a href=&#34;https://cordis.europa.eu/project/id/231620&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the project, we propose to take an
empirically successful, yet informal software development paradigm and
put it on a formal basis. Specifically, in HATS we will turn software
product family (SWPF) development into a rigorous approach. The
technical core of the project is an Abstract Behavioral Specification
language which will allow precise description of SWPF features and
components and their instances. The main project outcome is a
methodological and tool framework achieving not merely far-reaching
automation in maintaining dynamically evolving software, but an
unprecedented level of trust while informal processes are replaced
with rigorous analyses based on formal semantics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CREDO: Modelling and analysis of evolutionary structures for distributed services</title>
      <link>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/credo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 21:55:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ebjohnsen.org/project/credo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CREDO was a STREP project funded under the EU&amp;rsquo;s FP6 programme
2006-2009 (project no 033826). CORDIS website &lt;a href=&#34;https://cordis.europa.eu/project/id/033826&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In open distributed systems, the availability and requirements of components providing services vary over time. The networks need to dynamically reconfigure communication links between components at run-time in a context-aware manner. This reconfiguration includes the (dis)connection of components, but also the adaptation and updating of both components and the network. Updates may change the computation abilities of components and the coordination abilities of the network. For safety-critical systems, update should not compromise the reliability of services. Updates should be initiated and effectuated in a decentralized manner. No formal model of computation and communication exists today in which end-to-end system evolution can be expressed and validated. The use of formal models and validation techniques will significantly improve the confidence in dynamically reconfigurable systems, which are otherwise error-prone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aims at a compositional modelling and validation framework for dynamically evolving software systems, separating computation, coordination, and scheduling. Exploiting this separation of concerns, we develop a uniform modelling language in which object-oriented components are combined with flexible communication and timing models. A new notion of service interface is essential, allowing separate design and validation of different components and of the network. Interface composition enables end-to-end reasoning about evolving systems. These interfaces specify services and formalize the context awareness needed for run-time coordination and reconfiguration. The framework will help developers design and maintain systems by validating reconfigurations. We focus on automatable and compositional validation techniques, including abstract simulation, synthesis, model-checking, test-generation, and verification of interface compatibility. The usefulness of the framework is assessed through case studies, and by developing an integrated tool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
