<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sirius | Einar Broch Johnsen&#39;s Homepage</title>
    <link>/sirius/</link>
      <atom:link href="/sirius/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Sirius</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 Einar Broch Johnsen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 21:19:05 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hub341504972d314b2e9a402ad2e73d67e_181309_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Sirius</title>
      <link>/sirius/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sirius</title>
      <link>/sirius/sirius/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 21:19:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/sirius/sirius/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/sirius-logo-clean400.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sirius Centre for Research-driven Innovation&#34;&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;http://sirius-labs.no&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SIRIUS&lt;/a&gt; is a Norwegian Centre for Research-driven Innovation that addresses the problems of scalable data access in the oil &amp;amp; gas industry. The centre combines public funding for basic research with funding from its industry partners into an 8 year programme for industrial innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SIRIUS researchers are experts in IT technologies, including high-performance and cloud computing, formal methods, database technology, semantic technologies and natural language processing. The centre also includes researchers in the area of working practices involving novel technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The centre aims to provide the oil &amp;amp; gas business with better ways to access and use the massive amounts of data that are generated in projects and daily operation. Problems with data access are made more acute by the rise of big data, the internet of things and digitalisation of enterprises. SIRIUS targets these problems using an interdisciplinary approach, as successful innovation depends on the combination of technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The centre is designed to support technological innovation through a portfolio of projects. These projects develop basic technology in laboratory projects and then move the technology through prototypes to pilots in industrial applications. The centre&amp;rsquo;s intellectual property model is designed to build a core of open knowledge on which commercial applications can be built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIRIUS aims to be an intellectual hub for applied industrial IT in South-Eastern Norway. It has dedicated premises in the Department of Informatics at the University of Oslo and collaborates widely, both nationally and internationally. Many of the results generated by the centre will also be of relevance outside the oil and gas industry. The centre is therefore also active in communicating and applying its results to other areas such as Healthcare, Manufacturing and Public Administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://sirius-labs.no&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SIRIUS website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
